Speaker: Here is a standard deck of playing cards:
52 cards, four suits – spades, clubs, diamonds, hearts – 12 picture cards, two jokers.
Most people are familiar with these cards.
But what do they know about their history and their uses?
The first playing cards originated in Asia, probably in China in the 9th century.
Between the 9th and the 14th century, they traveled west across the world,
through India, Persia, and Egypt, to Europe.
The early cards looked different from the ones we know today
and the suits were different in different countries,
for example, cups, swords, leaves, bells, and roses.
The picture cards were all male figures, the king, the jack, and a soldier on a horse.
From the 16th century, the French deck of 52 cards that we know today became the most common.
Its design was simple and therefore cheap to print.
Why are there 52 cards?
And why four suits and twelve picture cards?
No one knows for sure, but an interesting theory is that the
52 cards represent the 52 weeks in a year, the four suits represent the four seasons:
spring, summer, fall, and winter, and the 12 picture cards represent the 12 months of the year.
The highest picture card is the king.
On the king card, the king always has a sword or an axe.
The kings also always have mustaches,
except for the king of hearts, who sometimes doesn’t have one.
The second highest picture card is the queen.
The French introduced the queen instead of the soldier on a horse.
On the queen card, the queen always has a flower in her hand.
In English decks of cards, the jack was originally called the knave.
However, because the initials of the picture cards appear on the corner of each card,
and there was already a “k” for “king,” "knave" became “jack.”
The jokers were first added to the deck in the 1850s.
They soon became a standard part of the deck,
and in some games they are “wild cards,” that is, they can be any card.
Playing cards quickly became very popular.
This was because previously most games were for two players.
Card games were ideal for a lot of numbers of players
and were especially popular with women.
The international 52-card deck is still very popular all over the world with people of all ages:
easy children’s games, games for one person, and serious games, like bridge or canasta.
But playing cards are not only for games.
Although there are special fortune-telling card decks,
like tarot cards, the standard deck was also a very popular way
to tell people’s fortune in the 18th, 19th, and 20th centuries.
The four suits represent four themes: spades are about challenges or difficulties,
hearts are about feelings and relationships, clubs are about positive things,
diamonds are about money.
Each number and picture card also has a special meaning.
You can have all kinds of fun with cards in many different ways.